Also, it's very important to mention he
never stops. Like on Sunday, that event
was over. We were like having breakfast.
He sits on the table and starts thinking
about a bug that he believes he just
found with with one of the Googers, Sam.
And Sam is like, "Dude, please chill."
Everyone's like, "Chill, man. Just
rest."
>> Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical think, right?
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
All right, hackers. We all know the
value of a good misconfiguration, right?
That's often how we're popping bugs and
bug bounties. Well, unfortunately,
Threat Locker also knows about it, which
is why they built DAC, Defense Against
Configurations. DAX scans all of the
enterprise machines in your network for
misconfigurations, ranks them by
severity, and then shows them in nice
graphics in a portal. It even emails
your team weekly with updates so nothing
slips through the cracks. And the best
part about DAC, in my opinion, is that
it actually maps all these
misconfigurations onto security
frameworks and it also shows you how to
fix them. That way, when you need ammo
with leadership or with it, you can
point to real specific compliance gaps
um and get actionable steps. Anyway,
check out Threat Locker DAC. It's an
awesome way to stay ahead of these
issues that we as attackers love. All
right, let's go back to the show.
>> Hey, what's up? So, this week on Bug
Bounty, we've only got one thing to
highlight, but I did want to share it
because it's pretty awesome. Um, you
know, my heart is near and dear to AI
and my heart is near and dear to our boy
Justin. So, you all will like this one.
Basically, there is a little uh
talk/weinar from hacker 1 called
securing the age of AI autonomy
priorities for 2026. And it's kind of
like a continuation of the really
awesome report they put out called Rise
of the Bionic Hacker, which you have, if
you haven't seen, it has some incredible
stats around like how hackers are using
AI, how many like what percentage of
hackers are kind of like leveling up
with it, what percent of companies are
paying out bounties for AI. It's a
really awesome report, but this
specifically is for the webinar, which
when this goes live might have already
happened, but if you register here,
you'll go ahead and get a link to
rewatch it. and they're going to be
interviewing people like Justin, Luke,
even James Kell from Portswiger Labs.
So, it's going to be an incredible uh
webinar and you should definitely tune
in to it.
What's up, guys? Welcome back to the
Critical Thinking uh Bug Bounty podcast.
We've got some incredible guests today.
Kieran has been here before, but this is
our boys bus factors first time. And so,
uh before I do intros, we'll have him
tell us about a cool bug.
>> All righty. That's how we started.
>> Okay. Yeah, you got to jump straight
into it. Straight into the deep end.
>> Okay, so um guys, I have this very
complex h yeah quite complex client side
heavy exploit chain cuz yeah, you know
that's me. So it's client side stuff. Um
so I have this huge questions about
that. So we'll come back to that.
>> Okay. Okay. Okay. Yeah, we're going to
do that. But um yeah, we got this huge
company and they have this support chat
and they they are not using intercom or
whatever. They have it in-house built
and I'm like okay that is not smart
because that's more expensive than
building it but okay let's take a look
at that and with some match and replace
rules I find out that the agent he can
access the customer not opposite like
the customer cannot access the agent and
I'm like okay how can I leverage this
without agent credentials and I'm very
proud of this one because it was like
everything you learn on the client side
world I'm going to use it right now
because because I start checking that
and it has no origin checks on the post
message. It uses post message for
setting up the chat, but it's also not
vulnerable. Like at the first look, I'm
like digging through the minified
JavaScript, which I love. It's like
>> it makes me good. It's like jumping you
guys. Oh, it pumps your blood.
>> And I'm looking into it. I'm digging
through the JavaScript and I find
nothing. It's been like four days. I'm
finding nothing. There's no origin
check. I'm like, I cannot believe it.
That is like stupid. But then one day I
wake up, I open the JS on a random point
and I see that there is this very stupid
thing they are doing which is a
JSON.parse
and object assign one after the other.
And if you don't know that that's like
textbook prototype pollution. It's one
of the ways to get that. And I'm like
okay how can I reach it? And after a few
like hours doing a lot of tests, I find
out that there is a very on one of the
post messages there is a very very deep
config property that you can control and
there is a if check a condition if it is
a string it's going to do the JSON.parse
and the object that sign. That's why no
automation was finding it because that
it was inside a branch of the code and
I'm like okay let's do it and I start
doing a lot of tests. I cannot do much.
I can do the prototype pollution or
prototype poison whatever you call it
but I don't get anything and then I find
this weird location whatever that is
version number in it in this config. I
change it and it actually changes the
host that it's using to connect the
websocket the websocket of the of the
chat. So instead of going to I don't
know chat.com/websocket
I can control it to go to my server
>> and then I can control the messages I
set up
>> yeah everything I set up this crazy
malicious server that was very hard to
do because I use I had to use everything
they were using like I think was like
socketjs something like that a weird
library and I got it working I do a lot
of post messages stuff setup connected
and I get the XSS and that's like almost
the end that's like one week just on
that one week and then I'm very close
but XSS has no impact yet because I do a
window open I open the support chat
domain whatever that is it's not inside
an iframe just a p just a page and I
start testing it and I see there's no
impact because it actually needs to
connect to the real host to get some
real data like PII whatever the
authentication token. So I have to use
another technique which is the iframe
sandwich and then I like I complete the
chain with a post message to prototype
solution to I frame sandwich because I
do a window open the support chat pop
the XSS open the product page that has
the the support chat and make them
communicate on the same origin and I get
a session take over because I can get
the authentication token and that's like
a bug I'm very proud of because they
used it in every page they had on every
product. So it was like
>> yeah it was scope changed.
>> It became a critical and they gave me a
50% bonus because they were like that's
crazy like they were like since you have
no social life and you've been doing
that for like a week.
>> That's what I'm going to ask. Is this
like an anchor program or a live hacking
target? Like how are you able to devote
so many hours to this?
>> I don't know what happened. It's like
just normal hunting normal day. I I
became like full-time bug bot hunter for
3 weeks now and I was like you know what
I want to pop this
>> and it was not the best um risk
management ever you know you would have
ran into a wall and not been able to
exploit it and it would have been so
much sunk time right
>> yeah but the bounty they paid was like
amazing that paid for a few months so
that that's all right you know
>> that's amazing
>> dude sweet well thank you for the
incredible bug Uh yeah, that chain is
absurd and I can't believe you had to
set up your own custom websocket PC
server to even get it going. But uh this
is the stuff I think that um you know in
the critical thinking discord you are
now known for. So yeah, if anyone
doesn't know Vtor, he goes by Bus Factor
>> and um he's been hanging out in the
critical thinking bug bounty discord for
a long time. I call him and some of the
other guys the front-end mafia. though
if you ever heard me say that Buzz
Factor is a part of the uh the front end
mafia but he's been bug hunting for
about a year and a half. Is that right?
>> Total before you went full-time.
>> Yeah, total. That's it.
>> But your first bounty was almost exactly
a year ago.
>> A year and two months kind of. Yeah.
>> Cool. Yeah. And then as of three months
ago, Vtor went full-time. Uh which is
absurd at how successful he's been in
such a short amount of time. But um you
know, I think it's just goes to speak to
his, you know, his quality. He also
leads hackalongs in the Discord and so
you know if people are in the Discord
I'm sure they've seen him lead those
hackalongs and if not you got to get in
there. Basically he and some of his
buddies were jumping in on Justin's
hackalongs and often converting tons of
bugs and Justin's like no you guys have
to do this. You have to do do it for us
as well. So anyways yeah so I just would
would love to hear more about your
background like why you know how did you
hear about Bug Bounty? What kind of got
you interested in it initially?
I don't actually remember how I got into
bug bounty the first time I was like oh
this is bug bounty and then you start
reading about it I don't remember like I
have no idea the only thing I know is
that few years like maybe five years ago
the first time I I tried it like I I
created an account on hack one I just
wanted money I was like I need some
extra cash this this got to be easy um
it turns turns out it is not and it was
quite frustrating I didn't. So I tried
it for like a week or two. I was like,
"Okay, no, that's that requires a decent
amount on investment and then I was
like, okay, I'm going to do it later."
And it took like four years to try it
again.
>> But I have no idea how I started it. But
I was like a developer. And after being
a developer, I became S, which is a
Google thing, right? Soft software
reliability engineer. It's kind of I
don't want to say that it was a mix of
DevOps and S. If I if Google people hear
me saying that S is DevOps, they they're
going to kill me and I'm not going to
get invited to another bug swat like
never again. But yeah, that that's what
I was doing. That that's my background.
>> Cool. Yeah, I was going to say um it was
very similar for me. I actually made an
account on Hacker One and then didn't
come back to it for years later. Um, you
know, I've been doing it for more like
five or six years at this point, but I
made my account like eight years ago,
but it was the same as you, right? Like
I got on there and then just hopped off
and then came back to it later.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, yeah. Well, one one thing I think
that uh Kieran wanted to ask you on this
call, which we'll get to the we'll get
to uh why Kieran's on the call.
Actually, I'll mention it now.
Basically, Kieran and BuzzFactor were a
dynamic duo in the most recent Google
live hacking event in Mexico and did
incredible. And so we've got them both
on here to talk about that in a second.
But he uh Kieran actually put in the
dock here, why are you called Bus
Factor? I'm also curious.
>> It's funny that he could have asked that
in person. So could you, you know, in
Vegas, but you guys didn't you wait you
waited for this moment.
>> That's exactly right.
>> Of course. It's it's a bit of a
disappointing answer, you know, because
if you don't know the bus factor, it's
actually a measurement of the risk you
get from keeping information and
internal knowledge from being shared
among members in a company. So think
about it. If you report a bug right now
to I don't know, let's say Google and
two months ago you're going to test it.
It is fixed plus two months you test
again and it it is there. They have a
regression. So why most of the times is
because they are not sharing knowledge
internally and they have no the
developers have no idea why the security
team was like hey can you change that
it's like critical they have no idea
they do not share the knowledge and
that's one of the things that I think
the bus factor is very critical to
companies coming from the developer
background I actually hated the silos
that were created inside the companies
made a lot of issues with secret bugs
but yeah but also functional bugs guys,
very stupid stuff. If you just turn your
head to the guy that's by your side and
say, "Hey, I'm doing this." That already
avoids a lot of issues and they never do
it. But knowing that, I was with my team
in London and buses there, they come
from the wrong way and I was very, very,
very close to getting hit by one just
because of that. I was looking to the
right. They were coming from the left
and that was like very close and I was
the leader of the SR team and everyone
was like if you die right now you know
that's like a huge bust factor for us
and they just started making fun of that
and that's cool.
>> I was like and then when I joined hack
the box we actually use our hacker names
in there like your email is not like
vtor at hack the box. No it's that's
factor at hack the box. They were like
it's time for you to decide a name. I
was like I can change I can change this
later right and then I put bus factor
you cannot like then
>> yeah that I would change it today you
know but it's too late
>> yeah exactly once once you get a handle
and it just sticks it stays with you
>> yeah I was I started in software
engineering as well and um but we never
called it the bus factor but we
definitely always tried to mitigate that
risk right like we we would even say
things like for example if Corey was hit
by a bus you know you know you say
things like that so you know you can
kind of like mitigate the downside of
one of your like important team members
getting uh something happening to them.
Oh, some people also call it I think
like a lottery something like
>> lottery factory.
>> Yeah, like a lottery factor. Yeah,
>> that's a bit more positive I think.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I'm going to circle back to kind of
your interest in frontend bugs um
because I want to jump straight to
getting Kieran involved here. But um
yeah, so uh Kieran, you know, I think um
you have been to several Google live
hacking events. You and I won NBA with
Justin and and Lupin back in uh the
beginning part of this year and you
know, I think that probably led to to
these these uh extra invites and
everything else. And you and you and
BuzzFactor did incredibly well at the
Google live hacking event. So do you
want to kind of I just talk about your
all's invitation and how you all decided
to collab?
Well, I initially, so I got the invite
from Mexico and I did like because I
worked with you guys like Ronnie and
Justin and you before, I was like,
"Okay, let's see if any of the others
are are uh invited." And none of you
guys were going and I was like, "I guess
I'm soloing this one." And then in the
like guild chat in the critical thinking
server, or I think it was the guild chat
or something, I saw Vtor saying like,
"Oh, I'll be at bug swat." I was like,
"This is perfect because I know Victor,
I've seen him around. I can just reach
out to him and see if he wants to work
with me. Thankfully, he did and it's
worked out.
>> Um, yeah, that that was kind of how the
collaboration came about. But like I
could already trust him because I'd seen
him so often in the space
>> in the critical thinking server
especially. So, you know, from the
get-go, we were like working together
really well, I think.
>> Yeah. If you're not uh familiar or if
you aren't aren't hanging out in the
critical thinkers chat, you got to hop
in there because Vtor is like very
active, very willing to help. and you
know um you know come up with some
complex chains or even even hop on
different programs or collaborate. Um
what was I going to say?
Yeah. So the tart so the primary I guess
kind of one of their main focuses for
that event was their AI features, right?
>> I would say yes and I also want to say
no. You were going to ask like things
about front end bugs, right? And I was
like, you know what? I'm going bug sweat
and I'm gonna do what I'm best at, which
is client side stuff.
>> And then I see Kieran. He's like, nope,
that's not the best you can do. If if
you want to like get the bounces, get
the reports, you got to focus on AI. And
I never ever touched AI before, but
>> Oh, so this is like your like first
foray into that thing.
>> Yeah, it was like first time ever. And
um I saw one of the guys, Blacklist, the
the French guy. He's a legend, right?
And he was like on live hacking events
you have to focus on what you know what
you feel comfortable and that for me is
client side
>> right
>> but Kieran was like no you're not going
to do that you're going to lose your
time doing that we're doing AI I was
like okay he he has the experience you
know I'm going to follow and see what
where it leads us.
>> Turns out it went great.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Tell us how it went. How
many reports did you all get?
So yeah, we got four. We actually got 16
reports. 14 of them are valid. The two
that are not are actually self dupes
that I could have reported more. And
then I got you one of the Googlers and I
was like, do I dare? No, don't. That's
going to be a dupe. And I'm like, okay.
So yeah, 14.
>> Nice. That's insane. And then you all
ended up winning uh second place overall
and winning the you know most bugs or
you know best bugs for the AI set
portion of the event. Correct.
>> Yeah. Yeah. We had um two show and tells
and we had best AI VRP researchers and
we had second place. Um so MVH was just
out of reach this time but you know we
can try again.
>> Well you gave me a little insider
baseball there and if we need to cut
this out we can. But yeah, you said that
you all only really got second because
someone found just something insane,
right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I don't I don't think
you need to cut that out. As far as I
know, some someone did something crazy
and
>> um well, a few crazy. They just beat us
to the
>> to the stuff. But
>> yeah, I guess it's kind of interesting.
It's kind of interesting to talk about.
Um
>> I know you all haven't been to a ton of
um Hacker One events. It does feel like
um at hacker one events MVH uh well I
guess it's always whoever finds the most
well no it's like the the mix of
criticality collaboration and something
else but yeah
>> yeah it does feel like um at Google
events they tend to uh heir on the side
of who has the most critical bug rather
than has like the most reports or even
the most you know um payouts for example
because I'd say across the last five or
six bug swats um it has felt like
there's only been one or two where they
paid out someone who had higher volume
and all the rest went to whoever had
like the most critical single bug.
>> Yeah. So I think um Google probably
operate similarly if I had to guess that
it is probably the three C's
>> but you know
>> but they waited a little differently
when they're actually thinking about it
I would say right or do you think that's
just a byproduct of just like how it
played out?
>> I I don't know. Um,
>> yeah.
>> Yeah. But yeah, we're pretty happy
anyway with the results, though.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Complain.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Cool. Did you all have any
other uh anecdotes or thoughts about
that Google live hacking event? You
know, you know, whether you recommend
Google or just like cool stuff that
happened or if you wanted to share a
bug, you could or anything.
>> Yeah. No, like we became we both became
friends with Adnan Adnan Khan who's uh
very active on like uh he does GitHub
action stuff. Great guy. Um, so we went
to like the on-site day in uh I I I
can't pronounce the name of the place.
It's like the Mexican Aztec temple and
we were like wandering around the uh the
area cuz the tour guides were like,
"Okay, you can like wander around or
whatever." And we're we were just
talking with some of the other hackers
and I realized one of them was Adnan.
Um, and I'd read his research before, so
we were like, we were chatting. Um, and
then we just started comparing all of
our notes and all the stuff we found so
far and, you know, where where it could
go and all of this uh, ideation.
Uh, and we and we we decided like, okay,
you know, let's like think about this on
the way back. We're like, we'll go and
get back to the bus.
And uh, we went to the wrong meeting
point.
>> Oh, no. And so eventually we realized
>> the bus factor missed the bus.
>> Bus factor almost missed the bus. Yeah.
So the three of us did this like walk of
shame back to the actual meeting point
and just got like applauded the minute
we
>> were all everyone's already there.
>> Oh no.
>> But after that, you know, we had a great
time with Adnan just figuring out more
bugs and stuff. We reported um a bunch
of stuff on site with Adnan as part of
our collaboration as well. So it was
really interesting to have that
difference in approach and and the
gadgets and stuff he piled up as well.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Also, it's very important to mention he
never stops. Like on Sunday that event
was over, we were like having breakfast.
He sits on the table and starts thinking
about a bug that he believes he just
found with with one of the Googers, Sam.
And Sam is like, "Dude, please chill.
Everyone's like, "Chill, man. Just
rest." And he keeps going. The guy the
guy is a beast.
>> Honestly, that's not that's not
surprising. I feel like there's so many
bug hunters that are that way.
>> Uh several people come to mind from
other events that do the same thing.
Honestly, I feel like Ronnie's a little
bit that way, Kieran.
>> A little bit. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool. Sweet. Um well, so yeah, let's
let's jump right back to that front end
thing, right? I mean, I'm sure that your
front-end expertise did play, you know,
a factor into some of the bugs that you
found there, but yeah, what what drew
you in? I mean, having only been in Bug
Bounty, you know, a year and a half and
only being full-time 3 months, like what
what do you like about frontend bugs?
Why has that kind of pulled you in?
>> So, for a whole year, I was only hunting
for server side stuff to be honest.
>> Yeah. And I I quite like it. I got like
good criticals in there. But at some
point I started hacking on which is an
amazing program and seeing what Justin
was doing at the critical thinking
community that's very client side heavy
most of them at least the people that
are quite active in there I started
trying it more and more and then in my
blog you can see that I I found one of
amazing bugs that was on a program bonus
client site
>> and I was like oh my god that's amazing
like I from CSPT to XSS and XSS to this
one didn't become account take over and
I was like that's kind of things they
find all the time that's crazy like now
I understand why people don't find it
you need to lock in you need to put a
huge chain and I'm like you know what
I'm going to do that on Epic Games on
Amazon everything I start doing it and
my development background comes in
because it's just basically reading
minifi JS you know and yeah it's
minified but it doesn't make it a gray
box review. It makes it white box. You
can set debugger break points and things
like that. And I feel like I feel home
when doing that. It's just easy for me.
And it's very hard to hunt for server
side stuff right now. When I start
trying, I immediately like my head
starts pointing me towards JavaScript
and stuff. I'm like, "Oh my god, I I
feel like I'm I'm stuck in here with
this." Or is it stuck in here with me? I
don't know. But that that's it. I just
think the white box review part of it is
nice. I love it. I like to understand
what is happening in there.
>> Yeah. It feels like I think a lot of
like server side stuff is almost like um
panning for gold. You know, you're like
you're trying to like you're you're kind
of like punching in the dark. You know,
you're you're you're fuzzing. You're
trying a whole bunch of like weird
payloads that might or might not work.
You don't know. you don't always get
verbose errors from like looking for um
like patch reversals or secondary
context. You know, you don't know that
they're there. You're just like looking
for them. Whereas, yeah, I think with
client side, like you said, it's more
code review. You have a lot of like
breadcrumbs. You have a whole bunch of
clues and a whole bunch of gadgets and
you're kind of like assembling a puzzle
rather than like, you know, you know,
kind of like uh shooting in the dark.
>> Yeah. Like from a problem solving
standpoint, I think client side's a lot
more satisfying when you you pop a a big
chain. um which isn't you know
financially server side is probably
better on average but client side is
more fun I have to say
>> yeah I do think client side often has
slightly more user interaction doesn't
it like you you often need like one
click or you need like um some sort of
water
>> difficult to yeah it's kind of hard to
affect many users at once
>> like even with good post message chains
you're usually still hitting like a
single user even for at so
>> you're like a step down in severity it's
hard to get crits you get highs most of
the time.
>> Yeah.
>> L luckily I think a lot of programs kind
of respect the hustle these days, right?
You know, they uh they understand the
difficulty with it and they're willing
to kind of bump it up, especially the
mature ones that people like you all
kind of target or hack on specifically.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Like there are definitely
programs that treat them as good as
server side, which is really really
nice. Mhm.
>> But yeah, during the event um Vtor was
like getting distracted with some of the
>> non AI stuff, but I was like
>> like do you remember in uh I think it
was Vegas where we got we went down this
rabbit hole of something and then Justin
kind of turned around and he was like oh
yeah guys there is bonuses. It is like
100% bonus or something that can wait
till after the event. Focus on the task.
>> Yes. So I
>> you heard you heard the ghost of Justin,
the the ghost of Obi here saying focus
on the event.
>> So I like channeled this ghost of Justin
into getting Vtor away from like the
rabbit hole and on to like like dude,
we've got bonuses to go for. Let's keep
on track. Um and it was the right move
in retrospect. Like it paid off really
well to do that.
>> Yeah, he did that for us in Tokyo too if
you remember at the table. basically
like always helped us like rep
prioritize
>> and that probably is a really underrated
perspective of full-time hunting, you
know, is like just that ability to
prioritize.
>> Oh, absolutely. Um, it's a it's a core
skill for bug bounty really that no one
really talks about.
>> Yeah, we mentioned it a few times, but
it's like there's not a lot of resources
out there and it's honestly hard to
build. It's it's like um it's a mental
model that you have to build for
yourself because it really does vary
depending on your skill set and some
people have a lot of success jumping
around and some people have a lot of
success going really deep you know and
so even though I think there are often
optimal decisions like the ones you're
talking about if you all had focused on
the ass stuff and found no bugs maybe
it' been better for Vtor to have like
found two client side mediums or
something you know like you can never
you can never know what the
counterfactual is but obviously it
clearly paid off for you guys because
you did really Oh,
>> and I think knowing the target, knowing
from before what Google accept and what
they look for
>> kind of helps to educate that decision
as well.
>> Yeah.
>> Sweet, dude. Yeah. Vtor, what do you
think has been kind of like the biggest
challenge of going full-time over these
last Well, one, let me just reflect on
the fact that it's absolutely ridiculous
that he's been this successful in only
three months of of doing bug hunting. He
like he literally was teaching the class
in the critical thinking server within
like a month of being a full-time
hunter. But anyways, yeah, what's what's
been the hard part or what's been
difficult for you?
>> So before becoming full-time, I actually
did plan for that for like 6 months. I
had like plan A, B, C, D, E, F. You
know, I was like, I'm fine. I have the
savings. I have everything I need. And
then I jump into it. And you may know
that I have Justin as my mentor, right?
And Justin is like, man, you have to
lock in in one program, only one
program. do at least a hundred hours in
it before jumping around. And that's
dude, that's very hard because it's so
easy to get frustrated. And I have this
thing that I get frustrated even easier
because of ADHD, which is something that
a lot of people has. And I was not
medicated by that time. Now I am again
like uh which is way better. But at the
same time, you have to be careful. And
now I can lock in more but not jumping
around like program to program and
getting that dopamine rush every time
you start a new program and start
finding low hanging fruits and things
like that. That is so hard. So locking
in one program like not not one program
to be honest. One app sometimes one
feature for hours is very hard but at
the same time it pays off so well. Like
that's amazing. The other things that
were like unexpected, they were not
really unexpected. Like you report the
bounty, the company sometimes takes like
three months to pay. Things happen on
the program side, on the hunter side.
That's like it is unexpected. You it is
expected plans, but you don't want it
and you got frustrated. It's not nice.
You need to handle that somehow. But
that's on the plans. That's big bouncy.
Yeah, that's so that's one thing I was
going to break up bring up is I think a
lot of people right now with AI and also
just the fact that Bug Bounty is now
like, you know, eight or 10 years old
are probably scared to jump in. I think
a lot of people have that fear that it's
like they're going to try to do Bug
Bounty and then there's going to be no
bugs left or no money left or anything
like that. What would you say to people
who are like, you know, considering it?
Like do you still think it's a good
decision? That sort of thing.
Well, uh, it's like people saying the
world will end tomorrow, next year,
whatever. You're going to have it every
year, every like people love it. People
love the chaos, guys. That's the news
that spread. If you say, "Oh, but bounty
will be good. We're going to get some
good money for years. No one want to
hear about it." They want they want the
the that chaotic news, you know, which
is
>> is a lie. Come on. The thing is you need
to adapt. AI is coming. You need to
adapt to that. maybe find AI bugs, put
AI into your workflow. It doesn't need
to be fully automated and kind of thing,
but it's going to be there. Now, if I do
recommend it or not, there are a lot of
things you need to think about before
doing that, right? Like, where do you
live? Is that in the US or is that like
me living in Brazil, which if you make
like two uh $2,000 a month, you have a
good salary for Brazil, you know? If you
do like two a month in the US, dude,
>> that's not good. That I'm sorry for you,
you know. So, there are a lot of things
to consider. I would say like do some
research. Critical thinking. Justin made
that uh full-time guide, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's been huge, right? It's
helped a lot of people, I think. Um and
I think kind of like that whole like
100k in a year if I had to do it all
again thread he posted that just keeps
doing rounds and people reshare it. I
think that's motivated a lot of people,
too.
>> But I have one thing to say about that,
guys. Justin has the superpower. He can
lock in for hours and hours and do it
over and over again. Be realistic with
yourself.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. No, I'm the same way. I think that
I'm actually uh undiagnosed ADHD and I,
you know, I'm actually I'll maybe I'll
talk to you offline about like what your
experience was like kind of
premedication and and having been
medicated because I've never taken any
medicine. Um and clearly I do fine, but
I do wonder what it's like to lock in
like that because it's a huge struggle
for me as well. Um cool. Sweet. Uh well,
I'm glad we got the chance to talk about
that. I know we we had that listed. Um,
yeah, let's go ahead and jump straight
over to the full-time bug bounty section
here. I think one, we were already
talking about it, but two, it's
something that, you know, I jumped in
full-time in January and Kieran, you did
at the same time.
>> It was about last year,
um, last April or something.
>> Last April. Cool. Yeah. So, I think, you
know, I think there are lots of thoughts
around that. Um, just listening to what
Vtor said, what kind of jumped out to
you, Kieran, about like, you know, what
are your thoughts on full-time bug
bounty?
Uh I I think I almost always recommend
keeping Bug Bounty as a hobby for most
people because
>> it is so many ups and downs. Like if you
don't get paid well in a particular
month because you focused on the wrong
program, like it's it's mentally very
difficult.
>> Um so I think keeping it as a hobby for
as long as possible is is wise, but for
the people who want that extra bit of
freedom in their life to do like
whatever they want, um it is just
amazing. And I wouldn't trade the
freedom for anything. like there's no
way I'll ever go back if I can help it.
>> Um yeah, that's my two cents on that.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I agree. I do think like um
I will say the people that listen to
this pod probably are in that like upper
10% or 5% of you know hackers because
they're like consuming all the Bug Bunny
content that is across every platform.
Um so for them it might make more sense,
but I think yeah, you're right. For the
vast majority of people, it's like a
perfect side hustle cuz you can do as
little or as much as you want all the
time. And it's just like extra money if
it works out. And if it doesn't work
out, you just learn some skills and
build your resume and who cares, right?
Like there's kind of like no downside to
doing it when you have a full-time job
as like hobby time. But the downside to
doing it when you don't have a job is
that if you don't make any money, you
don't get it. You know, you aren't you
aren't providing. So,
>> um
>> yeah. And yeah,
>> like I have friends who call it like um
beer money, but it's like they're quite
successful bug bounty hunters. It's like
what kind of beer are you drinking to
call it beer money,
>> right? It's more like champagne or
something.
>> Yeah.
>> I always hear that phrase champagne
problems for people who complain about
something that like is like actually
good or whatever. Um cool. Well, let's
do a round Let's do a round robin of all
three of us with like what your hacking
routine is because I think we're in
three very different parts of the world.
Um you know, being the the US and the EU
and then Brazil. Um, I'm curious what
your all's kind of like hacking routines
are like and and specifically maybe
mention like how much you hack per week
and then you know maybe if you want to
mention hours or whatever. I just think
that'd be interesting for the audience.
All right. Uh, I can start with that
that I try to keep as much as possible
of a fixed routine not change it a lot
because I think your body gets used to
like think well the same amount same
time every day. So, I usually do that
start like 9:00 a.m. sometimes 10. It
depends. Like there's a non-negotiable.
I need some kind of exercise every day.
Like either hitting the gym or fight PJ,
which is amazing. Get your body your
body very tired and then you go do some
mental stuff, you know, like working. So
like 9 10 I started. And I try to do
pomodoro sessions because they are
amazing for just keeping you focused.
And sometimes you want to like distract
yourself, think for thinking about
something else, and then you look at the
timer and you're like, "No, I can do
that in 10 minutes. In 10 minutes, I'm
going to have a break. Let's let's lock
in." So that's what I've been doing. And
also setting micro tasks, like things
that I need to do all the time, things
that I need to find out. So I just do
that every day from like 9 10 to 4, 5 at
most. Some days, let's be honest, some
days I do it for like 30 minutes. I get
tired and I go watch Netflix and but
that's that's the why I do it full-time.
That's why I do bug bond full-time.
That's the freedom I'm talking about. If
I need to go take my dog on a walk on
any time of the day, I can things like
that. But my routine is it's basically
that.
>> Cool. Maybe there you go. You go ahead,
Kieran.
>> Yeah. I have a question for Vtor
actually, which is like how often do you
really stick to that routine? like you
know I also try and kind of keep keep a
I I don't do pomodoros but I do have I
have like a morning session until
lunchtime and so on but I find it really
hard to stick to it if that makes sense.
Like that's the ideal for me but do you
succeed in sticking to that routine?
Yeah, during the morning and on Mondays
is a bit harder. But the thing that I
found out is that if on Mondays instead
of hacking I do something like for
example today we uh Defcon dropped a lot
of talks and videos on YouTube. That's
what I'm going to do for the Monday
because that's inspiration reading blog
posts that people have been releasing
during the weekend or last week things
like that. So on Mondays I do that since
it's a hard day. Instead of fighting
back against it, I kind of accept and
adapt. I think that's way better for
someone that has like ADHD ATD stuff.
And if if it is not working, I'm like, I
need to work. I need to work. It's not
working. Dude,
go I don't know, go to the gym, do
something, go for a walk, whatever. But
don't keep fighting. The only thing
you're going to get is next day you're
going to wake up frustrated, tired.
you're not going to be able to hack and
that's something that is not very
possible if you are working for huge
companies and things like that. So if we
can do that being full-time hunters, why
not, you know, why not use the freedom?
Why not use the idea of working less if
that's what we really want? So that
that's basically what I do.
>> Nice. Yeah, Kieran, what about you?
Uh yeah, I have like at the moment I'm
jetlagged because of the Mexico. Like
I'm still jetlagged. I have not
recovered from from the the jet lag yet.
But mostly I have like a morning session
if I'm awake in the morning. I work to
lunch, work into the afternoon, and then
I work from the wei work in Edinburgh.
So I'll get home before dinner and make
my dinner or whatever.
But I I don't use
um I keep a checklist of like my top
priorities for the day and I try and
knock them out in order of there. It's
in order of priorities. I knock them out
one by one. Uh sometimes I get none of
them done. Sometimes I get all of them
done. I also really go with the flow
most of the time. Um sometimes there's
stuff I really don't want to do and you
can't just go with the flow to ignore
it. So you have to kind of force
yourself. But yeah, I definitely echo
Vtor's sentiments that you need to use
the freedom you have when you're doing
full-time bug bounty cuz like otherwise
why would you do it? You're just doing a
9 to5.
>> Makes no sense.
>> Um so yeah, pretty similar.
>> Sweet. Yeah. And in fact, isn't there a
series called Day in the Life of a
Hacker or something that you're working
with getting published or something?
>> Well, yeah. Um Bug Crowd should have
that out this month sometime.
>> Okay, sweet.
>> Blog post on that. Yes. So, we'll have
more on that from you and also for me.
But, um,
>> yeah, for me it's like I definitely am
like kind of treating it more like a
full-time job this first year to make
sure that it's like ironed out and I'm
providing enough for my family of five
over here. But, it is really nice, like
you said, to be able to just be
interrupted and not care, right? If I
have like kids appointments or kids that
run in here or, you know, need to need
to get out or like like you said, BTO,
go on a run or go lift weights in the
gym. Um it's really nice to not have to
care or think or tell anyone that you're
going to go do that, right? Um yeah, for
my my schedule, I try to work like 8 to
4:30. Um but you know, lots and lots of
interruptions with kids, lots of
appointments, lots of sports, lots of
taking off early to go take care of
them. So
sweet. Um and then yeah, so the la the
last section that we really wanted to
cover here was um well actually any any
closing thoughts on full-time bug
bounty?
Yeah. To be honest, go ahead.
>> Go ahead. Yeah. Okay. So, go ahead,
Kieran. Then I go.
>> Okay. Sure. I think anyone on the fence
about it should just go for it. Like if
it's eating away at your mind like, "Oh,
should I go full-time?" You pro that
won't go away. That thought's always
going to be there. So, just jump into
it, dive off the deep end, give it a
shot.
>> Yeah. I will say for the people that are
uh considering it, they probably know
they're good enough to do it
>> and and they might struggle to take that
leap. At least it was for me. Every time
I would go to leave, my employer would
like give me a raise or give me a
promotion or whatever. And so, I do
think if you're going to do it, set
yourself a hard date. Like, assuming you
have the money saved up for the runway
and all that, set yourself a hard date
and like don't let anyone talk you out
of it because it's so easy to be talked
out of it just out of fear or out of
like another opportunity.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I'm meeting uh you know
Green Jam, he's at the Google events
sometimes. Yeah. He's coming to
Edinburgh tomorrow, so I'll be getting
dinner or whatever with him. I want to
ask him about his full-time experience
cuz he's just gone full-time. Very.
>> Oh, he did. When when did he start?
>> So,
>> oh, uh I mean, I think it's been like a
month or something since he's gone
full-time, but you know, it's been a few
years since he's doing part-time bug
bounty. So,
>> yeah.
>> Really looking forward to hearing what
he's what his experience is so far.
>> Yeah, that's awesome.
Yeah, I was going to say that doing
full-time hunting or doing any kind of
remote kind of work, guys, be careful
with uh social connections, you know. Do
not like isolate yourself and forget to
keep making friends and things like that
because we are all humans. Don't run
away from that. And when thinking about
making Bug Bounty a full-time thing or
not, you're gonna slowly stop treating
it as a hobby. To be honest, if you're
making money, is it really a hobby?
Like, you're making money that is paying
the beers or the bills. So, I was
already paying the bills instead of the
beers, you know? It was not a hobby
anymore by the end. That was a lie I was
telling myself to I don't know why. So,
be careful with that.
Yeah, that last thing is super true. I
definitely when I was working a
full-time job and doing Bug Bound on the
side, I kind of like felt like it was
like a game and so I would like justify
doing it all the time in the evenings.
And my wife is like, "No, it's work.
You're just doing work." I'm like,
"Yeah, I know, but I love it." And she's
like, "Yeah, but you're just working two
jobs. Like you're working all day and
then you're working all night." Like,
you know, like uh as far as like impact
on family, impact on your life, like
you're just doing two jobs. And I was
like, "Yeah, but it's so fun." So
anyways, I I made it the main thing so
that I didn't have to work two jobs. You
know, I think that a lot of people
probably that probably resonates with a
lot of people.
>> I think I've gone full circle there. I'm
doing pentests to pay to pay the bills
at the base level. Now it's back to
being a hobby for me, especially with
the live hacking events at this point.
>> Listen, you've doubled what you expected
this year, Kieran. So just everyone can
root on Kieran, and celebrate him as
well. You've doubled your goal this year
as a full-time hunter. You've definitely
given yourself the leeway to not have to
like do pin tests for your your bills,
>> especially after this Google event. Come
on. Before that, I understand. But after
the Google event,
>> no complaining.
>> All right. Yeah. So, um, one thing, you
know, I think that's interesting. I
think uh Kieran, you may have put put
this in the document, but um, actually,
let's just ask Vtor. This is your first
time ever doing Google uh, sorry, first
time doing AI related bugs.
Um, you probably had a lot of the
thoughts that me and Kieran have had
over the last year or two with like,
hey, these bugs are kind of weird.
They're sometimes like higher user
interaction. They're they're usually
targeting one user, so they're kind of
similar to client side bugs, but they're
often a little bit social engineery, and
they're also kind of weird because
they're non-deterministic. Sometimes you
got to like trial multiple times. Did
like just give me your thoughts on like
AI kind of VR like AI hacking in
general. um
having really kind of do dove in so
recently for your first time.
>> Okay. Um it was a weird feeling when I
popped the first bug AI bug by myself
because me and Mon were like covering
each other like he was burning out and I
was like okay so you chill now today
your day off. He had I don't know
anything to do and I was like I am going
to do some hacking and the day I popped
it by myself after learning a lot from
Kieran I was like okay that is weird it
feels like if I report this to the
company I'm scamming them I don't know
it doesn't feel like that yeah it
doesn't feel like a real bug that it's
going to happen 100% of the time
sometimes the prompt injection fails
things happen I I don't know I still
wrapping my head around it but I I got
this very interesting question on
Twitter a guy asks like should I learn
AI hacking or web hacking and I'm like
dude
>> it's a mix of both there's they do not
exist without each other
>> most of the excfiltrations we did used a
lot of decent good old client side
hacking like images things like that to
excfiltrate information if you don't
learn that you're not going to get there
delivery also use the same things a lot
of times Before the event, I was like,
hm, what is AI hacking? I don't know,
making AI on a company page say
something racist or anything like that,
like problem injection. I had no idea it
could be actually so impactful, like
leaking someone a company's data
>> or someone's emails and things like
that. And at least Google cares a lot
about that. I don't know how other
companies
uh deal with all this this kind of
stuff. I've seen a few reports on mostly
on the hackery one and the companies are
like we don't care that much. You're
going to pay as a medium at most high.
Google know Google is like
>> critical critical don't if you can
exprate anything that's a critical and
it's crazy you know I don't know how I'm
going to deal with AI hacks on other
programs. We have another live hacking
event in like two weeks, 3 weeks
>> and I'm going to focus on AI stuff
because
>> because whatever that's what I want to
do and I want to see what's going to
happen like I want to see how the
company is going to deal with that. So
yeah, that's the point I am right now.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And that's why I wanted to
ask you because I think it does feel
kind of weird. It feels a little bit
different like you said. Uh partially
because of the Yeah, it feels like it's
not that likely to be exploited, but it
is really nice that there are companies
at least like Google that do take it
seriously, especially when it can
control your IoT devices, you know, like
uh when there are really weird things
like that going on. And so uh and so
yeah,
>> sweet.
>> Yeah. Nice. Yeah,
>> this is the uh Google cam that I bought
to do some testing. But
>> yeah, it's
>> we may have made a run for a smart lock
in Tokyo. Like there's all kinds of
things you could potentially imagine.
[Music]
>> I think we're still at like a I think
we're at a very simple level of
complexity for a lot of these systems.
Like we'll begin to see a lot more like
server side issues, maybe MCP specific
issues or maybe it won't be MCP,
whatever it'll be. And similarly client
side issues coming out of the the
systems built on LLMs um in the next
like year or two as things get a lot
more you know the infrastructure and all
the libraries get a lot more complex as
well.
>> Um so right now it feels kind of scammy
because it's like oh what's the
exploitability but the minute you can do
some real like path traversal stuff
through tool calls I think it'll get
really interesting.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I mean, in that episode
where me and Justin interviewed um one
of the Google staff, you know, they were
talking just about how at their scale
when there's billions of users, it's
like this is probably going to get
exploited at some point, right? And so
it makes sense for them to take it
seriously, I think.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it does.
>> Cool. Yeah. Did you or you go ahead,
Vtor?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I just want to say that you
also have to think about the nonI
related stuff that is happening around
AI. Like think about I don't know, let's
put it Gemini. Gemini is getting huge
and they have to build features around
it like non AI related like having gems
sharing gems creating chats sharing
chats things like that. So we have this
AI gold rush. Everyone want to become
the best most sold AI product. Guys,
that's amazing. That means developers
making mistakes for a bug bounty hunter.
Like that is not amazing, but it is
amazing. You guys get it. That's
>> right. It's good for hackers.
>> Yeah. Yeah, you're right. They do have
to move fast, right? They feel this
really strong pressure to move fast. And
so, not only do they want to incentivize
bug hunters to look at them, I think
that's why Google's paying well. I think
there's that's why there's like really
good AI safety payouts. Like I mentioned
on a previous podcast with both
Anthropic and Open AI willing to pay,
you know, 25 or $35,000 for jailbreaks.
And I think it's because they really
want our they want our expertise and our
attention and they want it right now
because they have to release next week.
So they can't wait and so they have to
put a really heavy incentive on our
time. And so I think that you're right,
Vtor. I think that's like very um very
cool for us, right?
And like Google have updated their AIVRP
very recently.
>> So that's just a sign that things are
moving forward. Um and they're
restructuring they restructured some of
like what a P1 is and what a P2 is and
stuff in the new the new system.
>> Yeah. Exactly. So if anyone
>> Yeah. So if anyone's been confused about
why um when Vtor was saying like it was
like critical critical critical, it's
because of the the um attributes of
their report and with their new
reporting framework. like very clear.
So, if people are confused or curious
about how that's all set up, you can go
to Google's. We might drop it in the
show notes, but Google basically has a
new like AI VRP table on their rewards
and it explains exactly what would make
it an S1 or what would make it a P1 or a
P2, etc. And so, you can just go in
there and see exactly what the impact
and um would be and what the payout
would be depending on what bug you're
looking for. So,
um sweet. Do we have any other thoughts
on AI VRPs that you all did not get to
say yet?
Cool. Um, sweet, sweet, sweet. I think
the only other thing that I had for um
the pod was this is more of a little bit
of just like fun news. Actually, you
know, we'll save that. We'll save that
for um we'll do like a news episode.
We'll make this just like a fullblown
guest episode and we'll we'll do news
next time. Um, where can people follow
you or find you? I know you mentioned
your blog, Vtor. Go ahead and tell spell
that out for them so they can find your
blog.
>> Yeah, so it's uh Okay, that's going to
be hard because it's my my name. It's
vtor falcon.com.
That's where I've been posting more and
more stuff uh because it was I
forgot about my blog. Sometimes I forget
about it, guys. You have to do the
hunting and actually if you do the
hunting, you find
>> Yeah, that that's the point. like it
does, but it's very uh it's a hidden
it's indirect money, you know, the self
marketing stuff.
>> Yes.
>> But uh the thing is you have to do the
hunting and find cool stuff that you can
actually write about because there's no
point on writing. I don't know. I don't
know what I would write about if I had
nothing to talk about, anything nice
that I found during hunting or whatever.
I know Kieran does that. He just like
shares his accountability stuff every
week. I know you do that, Jazz, but but
that's not my style, you know, so it's a
bit harder for me.
>> Yeah, sweet. Yeah, I'll spell that out
quick. So, his blog is at vtor vi o r
falcow f a lcao.com.
And yeah, he mentioned his like
full-time hunting journey from the last
three months. So, it's a really great
read.
>> Sorry. Go ahead, Carolyn.
>> No, I was just going to also shout out
his uh first three months as a full-time
hunter blog post that he's done
recently. So, worth checking out for
sure.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And as far as uh Kieran, you
can find him at MonkeyHack on on on X,
but he also has Monkey Hacks, the really
nice um newsletter. So, you should go
subscribe to that.
>> And that's uh that's monkey.ie. M O N
keie.
>> Sweet. Cool. Well, thank you guys. And
we'll call that the pod.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.